Guide to the Stanford University Map Collection SC1049
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Maps
  - Properties of LSJU Map Volume, Series 10; 102 item(s)
    The maps in this category have been removed from the bound volume in which they were formerly kept and are now interfiled with the rest of the maps in this collection. They include maps of the campus as well as other University-owned lands. Campus subjects include streets, utilities (including water), trolley lines, athletic fields, land leased to Chinese workers, and Charles Lathrop's residence. Non-campus subjects include ranch lands owned in Tehama and Butte Counties, Vina Ranch, land owned in Lassen County, Oakland Harbor, Calistoga, and San Francisco.
    - Map of the Lands of Leland Stanford Junior University at and near the site of the University and in the counties of Santa Cara and San Mateo, California. (Britton and Rey publishers), 1908; MV001 (Box Na5)
    - Map of the Lands of Leland Stanford Junior University at and near the site of the University and in the counties of Santa Cara and San Mateo, California. (Britton and Rey publishers), 1908; MV002 (Box Na5)
    - Ground Plan of a portion of the L.S.J.U showing granite monuments and official grades [plan includes Main Quad, Chemistry, Museum, Library, Gymnasium], 1905; MV003 (Box Na5)
    - [L.S.J.U. street plan including section of University Park], 1900; MV004 (Box Na5)
    - [Pipeline, Searsville mains, and sewer mains plan for areas around Mayfield Avenue, Encina Hall, and east half of Quad], circa 1900; MV005 (Box Na5)
    - [Pipeline, Searsville mains, and sewer mains plan for areas around Mayfield Avenue, Encina Hall, and east half of Quad]--variation of MV5, circa 1900; MV006 (Box Na5)
    - Map of the Alvarado Subdivision on the Campus of L.S.J.U., in a southeasterly direction from the outer quadrangle, 1905; MV007 (Box Na5)
    - [L.S.J.U. plan includes insets of Roble Hall, Encina Hall and Chemistry Building ] Dakin Publishing Co., circa 1902; MV008 (Box Na5)
    - [Alvarado Row and Lausen Street intersection: Southeastern corner showing trolley line, Bookstore and Candystore], 1905; MV009 (Box C3)
    - Leland Stanford University [San Francisquito Creek and Governor Stanford's Residence, Menlo Park, SPRR] (abridged title), undated; MV010 (Box A2)
    - Plan showing Automobile Avenue at L.S.J.U. [routing proposal adjacent to University Avenue], 1906; MV011 (Box Na5)
    - "F" and "H" location lines and "R" and "Y" alternate lines near L.S.J.U. [Trolley lines], 1905; MV012 (Box Na5)
    - [Palo Alto Depot, Southern Pacific Railroad and Greer Partition], 1904; MV013 (Box Na5)
    - [Southern Pacific Railroad, Seale, Nash and Lathrop Tracts--prepared for Stanford], undated; MV014 (Box D1)
    - [Stanford University, Seale Tract, Greer Tract], undated; MV015 (Box A2)
    - L.S.J.U. and the Palo Alto Stock Farm, 1904, 1906; MV016 (Box Na5)
    - [Pasture Land and Mr. C. G. Lathrop's residence ground, Alta Vista, L.S.J.U], 1905; MV017 (Box A2)
    - Felt tract - compiled from records and actual surveys [San Mateo and Santa Clara Counties including Los Trancos Creek and Felt Lake], 1903; MV018 (Box Na5)
    - Felt tract - compiled from records and actual surveys [San Mateo and Santa Clara Counties including Los Trancos Creek and Felt Lake], 1903; MV019 (Box Na5)
    - [Creek Avenue bordering San Francisquito Creek and Governor's Avenue, including Orchard and Chinese Lot, L.S.J.U.], 1903; MV020 (Box A2)
    - Map showing location of spring and right-of-way for Country Quarry Water Supply [near Page Mill Road], undated; MV021 (Box A2)
    - Map showing location of spring and right-of-way for country quarry water supply [near Page Mill Road], undated; MV022 (Box A2)
    - Map showing proposed location of a reservoir for the town of Mayfield, on a protion of the lands - L.S.J.U., 1904; MV023 (Box C3)
    - Map of Stanford athletic field and vicinity, Stanford University, 1910; MV024 (Box Na5)
    - Survey of the fields between the Embarcadero, Automobile, and Country Roads, for L.S.J.U., 1911; MV025 (Box A2)
    - Survey of the fields between the Embarcadero, Automobile, and Country Roads, for L.S.J.U., 1911; MV026 (Box A2)
    - Topological maps of all lands situated in Santa Clara County, California, belonging to L.S.J.U. Surveyed at the request of F. L. Olmsted, 1886 - 1887; MV027 (Box D1)
    - Map showing properties of the L.S.J.U. and Spring Valley Water Works (abridged title), 1905; MV028 (Box D1)
    - Plat of Cedro Cottage and grounds, at L.S.J.U., 1906; MV029 (Box D1)
    - [Mayfield and Santa Cruz Roads, Menlo and Santa Cruz Avenues--street and tract map], undated; MV030 (Box A2)
    - Map showing a portion of the lands of L.S.J.U. and the Stanford Estate in Tehama and Butte Counties, California, outside of grant, undated; MV031 (Box D1)
    - Map showing a portion of the lands of L.S.J.U. and the Stanford Estate in Tehama and Butte Couties, California, outside of grant, undated; MV032 (Box D1)
    - Map showing the lands of J.S. Copeland, Tehama County, California, undated; MV033 (Box B2)
    - Map of the Copeland Ranch, Tehama County, California--property belonging to the estate of Leland Stanford, undated; MV034 (Box C3)
    - The Copeland and Schafer Ranches, Tehama County, California (abridged title) [one page from brochure "Estate of Leland Stanford, Deceased, unusual offering of Ranch Property"], undated; MV035 (Box A2)
    - The Copeland and Schafer Ranches, Tehama County, California (abridged for title) [one page from brochure "Estate of Leland Stanford, Deceased, unusual offering of Ranch Property"], undated; MV036 (Box A2)
    - Copeland Ranch, Tehama County, California [showing various orchards], MV0038
    - Portion of the Gerke Grant [along Deer Creek, near Vina Ranch], MV0037
    - [Deer Creek and irrigation ditches shows Stanford Properties, Tehama Co., California], undated; MV039 (Box Na5)
    - Stanford Durham Ranch, Dam across Butte Creek; architectural plans and details., 1914; MV040 (Box Na5)
    - Stanford Durham Ranch, Dam across Butte Creek; architectural plans and details, 1914; MV041 (Box Na5)
    - Map of part of Esquon Rancho [Butte Co., California], undated; MV042 (Box D1)
    - Gridley Ranch, Butte Co., California [Rancho Esquon and L.S.J.U. properties], undated; MV043 (Box A2)
    - Gridley Ranch, Butte Co., California [Rancho Esquon and L.S.J.U. properties], undated; MV044 (Box A2)
    - [List of properties in Lassen County belonging to Jane Stanford, with related documents], 1899-1903; MV045 (Box D1)
    - Sheep Range, Lassen County, California; with related document, 1918 - 1919; MV046 (Box D1)
    - [Lassen Peak Forest Reserve and Eagle Lake], 1907 - 1910; MV047 (Box Na5)
    - [Lassen County, California:Townships, Ranges], undated; MV048 (Box B2)
    - [Lassen County, California:Townships, Ranges; includes L.S.J.U. properties] (in red pencil: Stanford University 1910 3-15), MV049 (Box B2)
    - [Alameda Marsh Land Tract showing Stanford properties], 1907; MV050 (Box A2)
    - Map of Oakland Harbor. With notes re Stanford Properties., 1897; MV051 (Box D1)
    - Map of Oakland Harbor. With notes re Stanford Properties., 1897; MV052 (Box D1)
    - [Oakland Harbor and Alameda showing Stanford Properties], [1897]; MV053 (Box A2)
    - (Sanborn map portion of section 31 - near Livermore, CA), 1909; MV054 (Box C3)
    - Harbor line survey, S.F. Bay 1910, sheet No. 7, Point San Pablo to San Leandro point [Oakland Harbor], 1914; MV055 (Box Na5)
    - [Calistoga, California Tract map includes Stanford Properties}, undated; MV056 (Box Na5)
    - [Calistoga, California Tract Map], undated; MV057 (Box Na5)
    - The City of San Franciso compiled from the official surveys and engraved expressly for Crocker-Langley San Francisco Directory, 1904; MV058 (Box D1)
    - Map of the McCoppin Ranch, San Luis Obispo County, California. With related letter, July 9, 1910., undated; MV059 (Box D1)
    - Map of the McCoppin Ranch, San Luis Obispo County, California and Gwin Ranch, Contra Costa Co. ("Coon" and "Felt" Tracts, San Mateo and Santa Clara Counties, California on reverse side), circa 1897; MV060 (Box B2)
    - The "Coon" and "Felt" Tracts, San Mateo and Santa Clara Counties, California., undated; MV061
    - Map of the State of California showing lands belonging to Leland Stanford.1896. The Stillman Ranch, San Bernardino County, California [on verso]., MV062 (Box A2)
    - Subdivision of Lands in San Luis Obispo County, California (abridged title). With note re LSJU properties, May 31, 1899., undated; MV063 (Box D1)
    - [Southern Pacific Railroad with Seal tracts and Nash tract bordering Embarcadero Road, Palo Alto], undated; MV064 (Box D1)
    - Plat--showing lands of L.S.J.U adjacent to the town of Palo Alto, California [near University Avenue, SPRR and Parkinson Lumber Company], 1903; MV065 (Box D1)
    - Map of a subdivision of a portion of the lands of L.S.J.U in the town of Mayfied, Santa Clara County, California, 1903; MV066 (Box Na5)
    - [Topography, road intersection and lot planning in area of Cooksey Place, San Juan Hill L.S.J.U.], 1905; MV067 (Box A2)
    - [Leib Ranch, includes Area Bordered by Page Mill Road, Arastadero Road, SPRR and Edward Baron's Mayfield Farm], [1890]; MV068 (Box D1)
    - Map of a Survey Made for S.F. Lieb [Includes Area Bordering Mayfield Farm, Arastadero Road, San Francisco Road] (abridged title), 1882; MV069 (Box D1)
    - "Coon" and "Felt" Tracts, San Mateo and Santa Clara Counties, California ("McCoppin Tract" and "Gwin Ranch" on reverse side), circa 1897; MV070 (Box B2)
    - Felt tract - compiled from records and actual surveys [San Mateo and Santa Clara Counties including Los Trancos Creek and Felt Lake], 1903; MV071 (Box Na5)
    - L.S.J.U., Showing a Part of the Residence Grounds, to be Leased to the Chinese, 1903; MV072 (Box B2)
    - [L.S.J.U., Creek Avenue Bordering San Francisquito Creek and Governor's Avenue, including Orchard and Chinese Lot], 1903; MV073 (Box A2)
    - Right of Way of Southern Pacific Railroad Company Through the lands of the L.S.J.U., undated; MV074 (Box D1)
    - [Calistoga, California, Sewer Map], undated; MV075 (Box A2)
    - [L.S.J.U. Alvarado Row and Lasuen Street intersection: Southeastern Corner Showing Trolley Line, Bookstore, Candy Store], 1905; MV076 (Box C3)
    - Survey of the Established Line Between the lands of the L.S.J.U. and Mrs. J. Murphy, 1905; MV077 (Box A2)
    - Plat of Pasture Land Adjoining C.G. Lathrop's Residence Grounds, Alta Vista, L.S.J.U., 1908; MV078 (Box C3)
    - Map Showing Location of Spring and Right-of-Way for County Quarry Water Supply [Near Page Mill Road], undated; MV079 (Box A2)
    - Contour Map of Searsville Tract, 1912; MV080 (Box Na5)
    - L.S.J.U. Plat Showing a Part of What is Known as the Dennis Martin Ranch, San Mateo County, California [borders San Francisquito Creek], 1903; MV081 (Box B2)
    - Rancho El Corte de Madera with Rancho Canada del Corte de Madera [borders San Francisquito Creek], undated; MV082 (Box B2)
    - Plat of a portion of Lands of L.S.J.U. near Searsville, San Mateo Co., showing contour line at elevation of present dam of S.V.W.Works, 1894; MV083 (Box D1)
    - Plat of Cedro Cottage and Grounds, L.S.J.U., 1906; MV084 (Box D1)
    - Stanford Vina Ranch [Including Dairy Unit 4 and varied land divisions by acreage], undated; MV085 (Box C3)
    - Stanford Vina Ranch [Including sites for cemetery and east vineyard and varied land divisions by acreage - topographical], undated; MV086 (Box C3)
    - Stanford Vina Ranch [Including Dairy Unit 1 and other various divisions of acreage], undated; MV087 (Box C3)
    - [Lands of L.S.J.U. and the Stanford Estate in Tehama and Butte Co., California], undated; MV088 (Box C3)
    - Northern California Power Company's Pole Line shows lands of L.S.J.U. crossed by line (Vina Ranch), undated; MV089 (Box D1)
    - Gridley Ranch, Butte Co., California [Rancho Esquon and L.S.J.U.], undated; MV090 (Box A2)
    - [Rancho Esquon, Butte Co., California], 1867; MV091 (Box C3)
    - [Lands of Rice, Hamlin and Leland Stanford; includes Esquon Grant, Butte Co., California], undated; MV092 (Box B2)
    - [Alameda marsh Tract, includes Stanford property], undated; MV093 (Box D1)
    - [Lassen Co., California, Townships and Ranges], undated; MV094 (Box B2)
    - [Alameda Marsh Land Tract], with related document, 1909; MV095 (Box D1)
    - [Streets and lots near Oakland Harbor on property owned by Stanford University (Alameda ?)], 1907; MV096 (Box A2)
    - Map showing the lands of Honorable Leland Stanford, Butte Co., California, known as the "Gridley Ranch", undated; MV097 (Box D1)
    - Map of the Oakland Harbor Tract, Alameda (with memo), undated; MV098 (Box C3)
    - Map of a portion of the Town of Calistoga showing the lands belonging to Mrs. Jane L. Stanford, undated; MV099 (Box D1)
    - Map of a portion of the Town of Calistoga showing the lands belonging to Mrs. Jane L. Stanford, undated; MV100 (Box D1)
    - Map of a portion of the Town of Calistoga showing the lands belonging to Mrs. Jane L. Stanford, undated; MV101 (Box D1)
    - Map of a portion of the Town of Calistoga showing the lands belonging to Mrs. Jane L. Stanford, undated; MV102 (Box D1)
    - Portion of the Gerke Grant [along Deer Creek, near Vina Ranch], undated; MV037 (Box B2)
    - Copeland Ranch, Tehama County, California [showing various orchards], undated; MV038 (Box D1)
  - Other, Series 11
    - Five Houses for Mrs. Herbert Hoover, M910b
    - Five Houses for Mrs. Herbert Hoover, M910c
    - Five Houses for Mrs. Herbert Hoover, M910d
    - Five Houses for Mrs. Herbert Hoover, M910e
    - Memorial Church, M918
    - Bing Library, Education Building Area, M1102